Ashley Edds

252-425-5305 · Durham, NC · ashley@edds.net

https://linkedin.com/in/ashley-edds | https://github.com/ashleyedds | ashleyedds.com

About Me:

Currently enrolled in an intensive web development program and a healthcare practitioner with three years' experience working with patients in an inpatient acute-care setting, I am seeking a position which would allow me to utilize my experience in both domains and collaborate with clients to help them achieve solutions for their goals.

Education:

UNC-Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC

2018

UNC Coding Program (6-month boot camp) – Full Stack Web Development An intensive program dedicated to designing and building web applications.

East Carolina University, Greenville, NC

2013

M.S. Communication Sciences and Disorders

UNC-Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC

2011

B.A. Communication Studies *with a focus in speech and hearing sciences* Second Major in Linguistics

Work Experience:

Speech-language pathologist

Served as first point of contact for caregivers and acutely-ill patients and provided consultation on best plan of care in an inpatient hospital setting. Care focused on completing comprehensive evaluations and designing and implementing individualized treatment plans for patients who are unable to swallow safely and/or those who have cognitive-communication impairments. Work also included collaboration with a multidisciplinary care team with surgeons, doctors, and other healthcare practitioners as well as teaming up with patients' families to reach the best outcome for the patient.

Duke University Medical Center (Durham, NC)

2015-Present

Nash General Hospital (Rocky Mount, NC)

June 2015-February 2015

o Rex Hospital Clinical Fellowship (Raleigh, NC)

July 2013-May 2014

Technical Skills:

HTML 5 | CSS 3 | Bootstrap | Materialize | JavaScript (ES6) | jQuery | GIT | Github | Google Firebase | Node.js | APIs | JSON | Command Line/GitBash | MySQL | Express.js | Handlebars

Ashley Edds

252-425-5305 · Durham, NC · ashley@edds.net

https://linkedin.com/in/ashley-edds | https://github.com/ashleyedds | ashleyedds.com

Experience:

LocalScoop (Durham, NC)

2018

Full Stack Developer

- Architected a location-based news application for the web which utilizes Google Maps
 Geolocation and multiple APIs to display nearby news and weather. Firebase
 authentication allows the user to manage preferences and save locations and improves
 usability across multiple site visits.
 - https://github.com/ashleyedds/LocalScoop
 - https://ashleyedds.github.io/LocalScoop

FriendFinder (Durham, NC)

2018

Full Stack Developer

- Created a web application utilizing Node.js and Express, which invites the user to
 respond to statements about themselves. This data is stored in a dynamically-created
 API and their scores are converted into a compatibility index, which is then used to
 match them to their most-compatible friend.
 - Deployed utilizing Heroku: https://guarded-ridge-21146.herokuapp.com/
 - o https://github.com/ashleyedds/friendfinder

Reaction GIF Generator (Durham, NC)

2018

Front End Developer

- Designed a web-based application which creates buttons dynamically utilizing jQuery, searches the GIPHY API an returns the 10 most popular results.
 - https://ashleyedds.github.io/GIFGenerator/
 - o https://github.com/ashleyedds/GIFGenerator